VADIM GRIBANOV

Cracow, Poland

+(48) 516 937 979 \diamond mail@vadimgribanov.com \diamond Github \diamond Linkedin

SUMMARY

I'm a software engineer who loves to create awesome products that meet user needs. I have more than nine years of experience and a track record of delivering successful solutions. When faced with complex technical problems, I have a knack for troubleshooting and analyzing issues. I work well with others and value open communication. I'm comfortable working alone or in fast-paced environments. Learning new skills is a passion of mine, and I'm always looking for opportunities to improve my knowledge and expertise. Also, I'm pretty strong in algorithms - I've even won some national olympiads in informatics

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming Languages Ruby, Go, NodeJS, Python

Frameworks Ruby on Rails, Echo, NestJS, ExpressJS, VueJS, Django, FastAPI, React

Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, DynamoDB

Cloud AWS, GCP, Azure

Methodologies OOP, Domain Driven Design, SOLID, GRASP, TDD

Other Kubernetes, Terraform, Docker, ElasticSearch,

Twilio, Firebase, Wells Fargo API, Intacct Sage API

EXPERIENCE

Peer Street, Inc. (Los Angeles, CA)

June 2018 - February 2023

Senior Software Engineer(Independent Contractor)

Remote

- · Designed a financial product, that helped to attract over \$3000000 of new investments in 5 months
- · Implemented banking integration to simplify our operations with customers, which in turn increased number of customers' transactions by 44%.
- · Automated financial operations which lead to saving 20 hours per day for servicing department on average. These changes led to reduced servicing error rate by 20% and to increased overall revenue by 7%.
- · Improved financial data consistency, reduced data loss by processing customers' operations in a transactional way. This change gave us a better observability, reduced time required to make data correction requests by 50%
- · Promoted Domain Driven Design and Clean Code approach to improve our design/development process, as well as platform maintance
- · Reviewed code and helped trend set high quality standards for other engineers.
- · Gave fast feedback to product managers about upcoming features complexity.

Silicon Valley Software Group LLC (San Francisco, CA)

March 2016 - April 2018

Remote

 $Software\ Engineer(Independent\ Contractor)$

- · Leaded a team of three frontend developers.
- · Designed and developed multiple complex frontend application from scratch using React and Node.
- · Promoted unit tests and integration tests. As a result, we increased stability of the application.
- · Setup automated code reviews with linters and configured CI/CD pipeline using TravisCI, CircleCI and GithubActions.
- · Reviewed code and mentored other devs.
- · Improved code quality of multiple projects after active development

· Configured production server to serve frontend assets from CDN.

Appeast Inc. (Boston, MA)

Ruby on Rails Developer

October 2015 - February 2016

Minsk, Belarus

- · Implemented API service built on Ruby on Rails.
- · Refactored and optimised Cost Per Action estimation algorithm.
- · Implemented UI features in web application built on Angular.

SivinTech LLC

December 2014 - September 2015

Minsk, Belarus

Ruby on Rails developer

- · Designed and implemented call center for the client of SivinTech. Used Twilio as communication platform.
- · Migrated old Java applet to Angular.

EDUCATION

Belarusian State University Of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk

2013 - 2017

Faculty of Computer Systems and Networks

B.S. in Computer Science & Software Engineering

Belarusian State University Of Informatics and Radioelectronics, Minsk

2017 - 2020

Faculty of Computer Systems and Networks

M.S. in Computer Science

incomplete degree

HONORS & AWARDS

Competed in RuCTF 2015 competition as part of the team from our university. Our team took 2nd place.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2013. Took 1st degree diploma.

Competed in Individual Olympaid in Informatics and Programming in 2013. Took awardee diploma.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2012. Took 2nd degree diploma.

Competed in Belarus National Olympiad in Informatics in 2011.

LINKS

Github - https://github.com/yoihito

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/yoihito/